Guide to the Richard Sterling Finnie Papers, 1950-1967
Department of Special Collections
Finnie, Richard Sterling Papers,
1950-1967
M0694
Finnie, Richard Sterling.
6 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
22 Photographs, 31 audio tapes and 28 films relating to many of Bechtel Corporation's major construction projects.
Administrative Information
Access
None.
Biography
Historian for Bechtel Corporation and professional photographer.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
22 Photographs, 31 audio tapes and 28 films relating to many of Bechtel Corporation's major construction projects.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Bechtel Corporation.; Engineering.; Science--History.; Motion pictures.; Phonotapes.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Photographs
  - Minas - Duri 26" pipline, Sumatra.1958, color (Othertype 1)
  - B. P.'s Aden Refinery1957, color (Othertype 2)
  - Tangin-Ri Power Plant, Republic of Korea1956, color (Othertype 3)
  - Aramco Adrainistration Building, Dhahran1957, b/w (Othertype 4)
  - Ras Tanura Refinery1957, b/w (Othertype 5)
  - Babco Refinety, Babrain1957, b/w (Othertype 6)
  - Damrriam Pier, Saudi Arabia1957, b/w (Othertype 7)
  - Bejamin F. Fairless with George Colley at Puerto Orday, Feb. 19531953, b/w (Othertype 8)
  - Gas Flare, Kuwait1957, b/w (Othertype 9)
  - Jiddah Pie1957, b/w (Othertype 10)
  - Oil Loading Jetty, Mina al Ahmadi, Kuwait1957 (Othertype 11)
  - Electrification of Riyadhn. d., color (Othertype 12)
  - Donkey well, Saudi Arabian.d., color (Othertype 13)
  - Bapco Oil Loading Pier, Bahrain1957, b/w (Othertype 14)
  - Surf Club, Ras Tanura1957, b/w (Othertype 15)
  - Dammam Pier, Saudi Arabia .1957, b/w (Othertype 16)
  - Oil Loading Piers, Ras Tanura1957, b/w (Othertype 17)
  - Ras Tanura Refinery1957, b/w (Othertype 18)
  - [Lakehead Pipeline Extension, Straits of Mackinac crossing] 6 men, standing1958, color (Othertype 19)
  - Desulfurizer, Ras Tanura1957, b/w (Othertype 20)
  - Jidda Piern.d., color (Othertype 21)
  - Hangar in consthiction, Jidda1950, color (Othertype 22)
- Series 2. Audiotapes
  - GCOS Dedication 9/30 1967 (Sept. 30) Part I1967 (Othertype 1)
    1. Bill Dunlop: "0 Canada"; 2. Rev. P.G. Harris; 3. Kenneth F. Heddon, Pres. Sun Oil Co.; 4. Clarence H. mayer, Pres. GCOS; 5. S. D. Bechtel, Sr.
  - Dr. Mortimer J. Adler: "World Peace and the Human Mind"1958 (Othertype 2)
    Industrial Indemnity lecture, San Francisco, 24 Nov. 1958 Excerpts Intro, Conclusion w/clipping, invitation in box
  - Pipeline Equipment Euro tests Aug. 14-15, 19551955 (Othertype 3)
    S. P. Project Finnie for Engineering Management Inc.
  - GCOS dedication Roll 3 30 Sept. 19671967 (Othertype 4)
    Robert G. Dunlop, Pres. Sun Oil Company
  - GCOS Dedication Roll 2 30 Sept. 1967 and clipping, Oct. 1969 about Winters ' death; S.D. Bechtel Sr. concluded, Clarence Thayer, Harold Rea, Robert Winters (runs out)1967 (Othertype 5)
  - (Reel 7) Monterey Seminar - Feb. 1957 R.M. Dorman, chairman1957 (Othertype 6)
    Dr. Douglas Kelly, UoC Psychologist, on Communication: Canalization, Prejudice, as, etc. (Same lecture as on Reel 6 with minor variation.)
  - Feb. 14, 1957 Roll 2 Thurs. afternoon1957 (Othertype 7)
    List of names in box, 4 pp.
  - Roll 2 Feb. 7. Thurs. PM. Exposed (1957 Monterey Seminar)1957 (Othertype 8)
  - Fri. AM Roll 4 Monterey Seminar Feb. 19571957 (Othertype 9)
    1 p. list of names
  - Fri. Feb. 15, 1957 Roll 5, list enclosed1957 (Othertype 10)
  - Roll 8, Sat. AM 1957 (Feb. 16)1957 (Othertype 11)
    Kelly, Phelan, Swanson, 0 ' Connell
  - Cerro Bolivar - Spanish, part 21954 (Othertype 12)
    Eduardo Zavraga - Spanish narration "Iron Ore from Cerro Bolivar, 1954, Caracas
  - Cerro Bolivar - Spanish, part 11954 (Othertype 13)
  - Oct. 5, 1960 S .D. Bechtel - NDTA, New Orleans1960 (Othertype 14)
  - Sound Effects and running commentary: steel making and pipe fabrication. For Richard Finnie's film "Southern Pacific Pipeline, Aug 3-6, 19551955 (Othertype 15)
  - Fri. afternoon Speech Instructor Roll 6 Feb. 15, 19571957 (Othertype 16)
  - Bechtel Management Monterey Seminar Feb. 1957 Roll 5 11: 3OAM - 4 PM Friday the 15th1957 (Othertype 17)
    Discussion of hypothetical job - personality situation followed by role playing by paiticipants Dr. Gerry Phelan lectures on conference conducting list enclosed
  - Roll 1, 1957 Thurs. AM after coffee break - Feb. 14, 19571957 (Othertype 18)
    list enclosed
  - Sirbica Pipeline - Arabic narration voice: Issa Belkheir 17 Feb. 19651965 (Othertype 19)
  - Seminar - Roll 6 - Fred Stripp - Prof. of Forensics, UoC, Douglas Kelley, Psychologist, UoC1957 (Othertype 20)
  - Roll 3, list end. Seminar Feb. 571957 (Othertype 21)
  - 1st seminar, Roll 1, Roll 81957 (Othertype 22)
  - Roll 4 2nd Conf.1957 (Othertype 23)
  - Sirtica Pipeline - Arabic narration, voice: Issa Belkheir, Thipoli, Libya, 17 Feb. 1965, original1957 (Othertype 24)
  - US Steel - Mr. Fairless speech 1/25/541954 (Othertype 25)
    Jan. 10, 1954 Benjamin F. Fairless at Fairless Works dockside for unloading of first iron ore from Cerro Bolivar
  - Panama Refinery Film "Petroleum Pioneering in Panama"1963 (Othertype 26)
    Narration for Spanish version: Precursores del Petroler en Panama" voice: Arguimedes Fernandez - 1 June 1963
  - Navy ' s recording of Mr. Bechtel ' Speech and part of the presentation speech of Dr. Germane.1960 (Othertype 27)
    N.D.TA speech - New Orleans, 1960
  - Seminar - Gerry Phelan, Win. Swanson, J. Perry Yates Roll 91957 (Othertype 28)
  - 17 Nov. 1966 Jr. & Sr. Bechtel, Yates-Bechtel Film Dialogue1966 (Othertype 29)
  - Economics Dr. Homan - 12/29/69 ~ Discussion of mid-term Kiely Speech Rehearsal 15 Sept. 19671969 (Othertype 30)
  - Refineria Panama S .A. (Othertype 31)
- Series 3. Films
  - "A Visit to Venezuela", color, sound 16mm 36 min. (Othertype 1)
  - "A Visit to Venezuela", color, sound l6mm 35 min. (Othertype 2)
  - "A Visit to Venezuela", color, sound 16mm 36 min (Othertype 3)
  - "Builders for Industry" Portrait of a Business Family, 1953, color, sound 16mm 38 min (Othertype 4)
  - "Oil Across Arabia, " (The Tapline Project). Edited version, color, sound 20 min. (Othertype 5)
  - "Oil Across Arabia" The 1068 nm 30-31 "Trans-Arabia pipeline System from the oil fields of Saudi arabia to the Mediterranean Sea, 1951, color,sound 44 min. (Othertype 6)
  - "Bechtel in Arab lands, " Engineering and construction projects in Middle East since 1943, 1958, color, sound 60 min. (Othertype 7)
  - "New Fuel for New England, " Construction of 225 mile natural gas lateral pipelines in Conn, Mass, 'New Hang, for Norbheastern Gas and Transmission Company, May-Aug 1952, color, sound 15 min. (Othertype 8)
  - "New Fuel for New England, " Construction of 225 mile natural gas lateral pipelines in Conn, Mass, 'New Hang, for Norbheastern Gas and Transmission Company, May-Aug 1952, color, sound 15 min. (Othertype 9)
  - "Chocolate Bayou, " Monsanto Chemical Company's Chocolate Bayou petrochemical complex near Alvin, DC, 1963, color, sound l6 mm 20 min. (Othertype 10)
  - "More Power to Korea" The engineering and construction of steam-electric power plants for the Republic of Korea, color, sound 40 mm. (Othertype 11)
  - "Kirkuk to Banias, " Iraq Petroleum Company's 556 mile 26-30-32 crude oil pipeline from Kirkuk, Iraq to Banias, Syria, color, sound 16mm 36 min. (Othertype 12)
  - "Bechtel in Europe, " Bechtel engineering - management experience and capability in the British Isles and Western Europen, 1964, color, sound 40 min. (Othertype 13)
  - "More Power to Korea", 40 min. (Othertype 14)
  - "Oil Across Arabia," 1951 (Othertype 15)
  - "Oil from Zarzaltine," building of the 470 mile pipeline from the Sahara through Tunisia to a new oil loading port on the Mediterraneancolor,sound l6mm 40 min. (Othertype 16)
  - "Iron Ore from Cerro Bolivar, " US Steel's Iron-ore development project in S .E. Venezuela, beginning with early reconnaissance and ending with the unloading of the let iron ore from Cerro Bolivar at the Fairless Works, near Philadelphia, 1954, 38 min (Othertype 17)
  - "Kirkuk to Banias, " 1951-52, 36 min (Othertype 18)
  - "Engineers & Builders for Industry, " the background, present-day structure, capabilities and variety of activities of Bechtel Corp. and its affiliates around the world. Short version, 1967, 26 min (Othertype 19)
  - "Oil Across Sumatra, " A story of petroleum of Sumatra--how, after oil had been found, the problem was solved of moving it from wells deep in the jungle to the iuarkets of the world, 1959, 28 min. (Othertype 20)
  - "Challenge of Capricorn - A Joint Ampol-Bechtel film on the buildings of Queensland first and Australia ' s most modern petroleum refineiy, near Brisbane, 1965, color, sound l6mm 27 min. (Othertype 21)
  - "A.U.B. " Documentary film on the American University of Beirut, Lebanon, 1952, color, sound 28 min. (Othertype 22)
  - "Refinery in Aden, " the construction of the British Petroleum Company Ltd ' s refinery in Men, 1954, color, sound l6mm 31 min. (Othertype 23)
  - "Exploring Libya", color, sound l6mmn 29 min. (Othertype 24)
  - "A.U.B." (Othertype 25)
  - "Southern Pacific Pipeline" Engineering & Construction of S.P.'s LA-El Paso refinery products pipeline system, 1956sound,color 28 min. (Othertype 26)
  - "Pipeline from the Peace to the Pacific," 1958, color (Othertype 27)
  - "The Fabulous Oil Sands" (Othertype 28)